Guide to the Alexander Mordecai Bickel Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- SHORTER WRITINGS, 1954-1974; Series III; .25 linear feet (7 boxes)
  - The New Republic
    - "After the Arrest: Interrogation and the Right to Counsel", 1966 February 12 (Box 19, Folder 62)
    - "Making the Best Use of the Police Force", 1966 March 12 (Box 19, Folder 63)
    - "Four-Year Term" (House of Representatives), 1966 March 12 (Box 19, Folder 63)
    - "Obscenity and the Law", 1966 April 3 (sic) (Box 19, Folder 63)
    - "Forcing Desegregation through Title VI", 1966 April 9 (Box 19, Folder 63)
    - "LBJ's Civil Rights Bill", 1966 May 21 (Box 19, Folder 64)
    - "Station House Confessions", 1966 June 25 (Box 19, Folder 64)
    - "Housing in the House", 1966 July 30 (Box 19, Folder 64)
    - "Civil Rights' Dim Prospects", 1966 September 17 (Box 19, Folder 64)
    - "Courts and the Press", 1966 October 15 (Box 19, Folder 65)
    - "Backlash Jitters", 1966 October 22 (Box 19, Folder 65)
    - "Kennedy Assassination", 1966 November 12 (Box 19, Folder 65)
    - "What is the Law?" (Georgia election law), 1966 December 24 (Box 19, Folder 65)
    - "Reexamining the Warren Report", 1967 January 7 (Box 20, Folder 66)
    - "The Case for the Electoral College", 1967 January 28 (Box 20, Folder 66)
    - "Law and Prudence in the Powell Case", 1967 February 25 (Box 20, Folder 67)
    - "Hospital Segregation", 1967 March 25 (Box 20, Folder 68)
    - "Antitrust Slowdown?", 1967 May 20 (Box 20, Folder 69)
    - "Obscenity Cases", 1967 May 27 (Box 20, Folder 70)
    - "Thurgood Marshall", 1967 June 24 (Box 20, Folder 70)
    - "Skelly Wright's Sweeping Decision" (school desegregation), 1967 July 8 (Box 20, Folder 70)
    - "CBS on the Warren Report," with transcripts of the broadcasts, 1967 July 15 (Box 20, Folder 71)
    - "Death Penalty Litigation", 1967 August 19 (Box 20, Folder 72)
    - "Death Penalty Litigation": briefs, 1967 August 19 (Box 20, Folder 73)
    - "Death Penalty Litigation": petition for certiorari, 1967 August 19 (Box 20, Folder 74)
    - "Gone North" (voter registration in Gary), 1967 November 18 (Box 20, Folder 74)
    - "Hershey and the Draft", 1967 December 2 (Box 20, Folder 74)
    - "Supreme Court: Internal Security Cases", 1968 January 6 (Box 20, Folder 74)
    - "Unconstitutional Bugging", 1968 January 6 (Box 20, Folder 75)
    - "The Fearsome Five" (Coffin, Spock et al.), 1968 January 20 (Box 20, Folder 75)
    - "What Dirksen Knows" (electoral reform), 1968 January 27 (Box 20, Folder 75)
    - "Spock-Coffin Case", 1968 March 2 (Box 20, Folder 75)
    - "Answer to Wallace" (electoral reform), 1968 March 9 (Box 20, Folder 76)
    - "The Belated Civil Rights Legislation of 1968", 1968 March 30 (Box 20, Folder 76)
    - "The Senate Judiciary's Abominable Crime Bill", 1968 May 25 (Box 20, Folder 77)
    - "Crime Bill", 1968 June 8 (Box 20, Folder 78)
    - "The Kennedy Cause", last four paragraphs, 1968 June 15 (Box 20, Folder 78)
    - "Crime, the Courts, and the Old Nixon", 1968 June 15 (Box 20, Folder 78)
    - "Spock-Coffin", 1968 June 29 (Box 20, Folder 78)
    - "Charge at the Court", 1968 July 6 (Box 20, Folder 79)
    - "The Chief Justice", 1968 July 20 (Box 20, Folder 79)
    - "A Communication: The Kennedy Cause", 1968 July 20 (Box 20, Folder 79)
    - "There Comes a Time…" (third parties), 1968 August 3 (Box 20, Folder 79)
    - "Fortas, Johnson and the Senate", 1968 September 28 (Box 20, Folder 80)
    - "Race and Schools", 1968 October 12 (Box 20, Folder 80)
    - "Schools and Title VI", 1968 October 19 (Box 20, Folder 80)
    - "After Fortas", 1968 October 19 (Box 20, Folder 80)
    - "Electing Presidents", 1968 November 30 (Box 21, Folder 81)
    - "Electoral College", 1968 December 14 (Box 21, Folder 81)
    - "Equity and Electoral Reform", 1969 January 11 (Box 21, Folder 81)
    - "Caretakers of Justice", 1969 February 1 (Box 21, Folder 82)
    - "JFK Assassination", 1969 February 1 (Box 21, Folder 82)
    - "Democratic Reform", 1969 February 8 (Box 21, Folder 82)
    - "Electing Presidents", 1969 February 22 (Box 21, Folder 82)
    - "Politics for Every Man", 1969 March 8 (Box 21, Folder 83)
    - "Electoral Reform", 1969 March 15 (Box 21, Folder 83)
    - "Conscientious Objection", 1969 May 3 (Box 21, Folder 83)
    - "Wait a Minute!" (electoral reform), 1969 May 10 (Box 21, Folder 84)
    - "Mr. Justice Fortas", 1969 May 17 (Box 21, Folder 84)
    - "Fortas Resignation", 1969 May 24 (Box 21, Folder 84)
    - "The Chief Justice", 1969 May 31 (Box 21, Folder 85)
    - "Outside Income" (William O. Douglas), 1969 June 7 (Box 21, Folder 85)
    - "Earl Warren vs. Warren Earl", 1969 June 28 (Box 21, Folder 85)
    - "Bugging 'Subversives'", 1969 July 5 (Box 21, Folder 86)
    - "Robert Kennedy as History", 1969 July 5 (Box 21, Folder 86)
    - "Close of the Warren Era", 1969 July 12 (Box 21, Folder 87)
    - "Invisible Appointments" (G. Harrold Carswell), 1969 July 12 (Box 21, Folder 87)
    - "Spock-Coffin", 1969 July 26 (Box 21, Folder 88)
    - "How to Beat Crime", 1969 August 30 (Box 21, Folder 88)
    - "Nixon's Court", 1969 August 30 (Box 21, Folder 88)
    - "Student Demands and Academic Freedom", 1969 September 20 (Box 21, Folder 88)
    - "Misreading Democracy" (electoral reform), 1969 September 27 (Box 21, Folder 89)
    - "Haynsworth Nomination", 1969 October 4 (Box 21, Folder 89)
    - "Does It Stand Up?" (Haynsworth), 1969 November 1 (Box 21, Folder 89)
    - "What the Court Said" (school desegregation), 1969 November 15 (Box 21, Folder 90)
    - "After Haynsworth", 1969 December 13 (Box 21, Folder 90)
    - "The Right to Vote", 1970 January 3 (Box 21, Folder 90)
    - "Haynsworth to Carswell", 1970 January 31 (Box 21, Folder 91)
    - "About Democracy" (McGovern Commission), 1970 February 7 (Box 21, Folder 91)
    - "Desegregation: Where Do We Go From Here?", 1970 February 7 (Box 21, Folder 92)
    - "No to Carswell", 1970 February 28 (Box 21, Folder 93)
    - "Stennis and Schools", 1970 February 28 (Box 21, Folder 93)
    - "Realistic, Sensible" (school desegregation), 1970 April 4 & 11 (Box 21, Folder 93)
    - "Consent to Carswell", 1970 April 4 & 11 (Box 21, Folder 93)
    - "On the Bench", 1970 April 25 (Box 21, Folder 94)
    - "Eighteen-year-old Vote", 1970 May 2 (Box 21, Folder 94)
    - "The War-Making Power", 1970 June 6 (Box 21, Folder 94)
    - "The Tolerance of Violence on Campus", 1970 June 13 (Box 21, Folder 95)
    - "Wallace in '72", 1970 June 20 (Box 21, Folder 96)
    - "Keep It Brief" (18-year-old vote), 1970 June 20 (Box 21, Folder 96)
    - Reply to "The Urban Vote" (electoral reform), 1970 June 27 (Box 21, Folder 96)
    - "Conscientious Objection", 1970 July 18 (Box 21, Folder 96)
    - "Direct Election of the President", 1970 September 26 (Box 21, Folder 97)
    - "The Revolution of Unreason", 1970 October 17 (Box 21, Folder 97)
    - "Canada Can, Can We?" (martial law), 1970 October 31 (Box 21, Folder 98)
    - "Justice Douglas", 1971 January 9 (Box 21, Folder 98)
    - "Electing a president", 1971 February 13 (Box 21, Folder 98)
    - "Filibusters", 1971 February 20 (Box 21, Folder 98)
    - "Conscientious Objection", 1971 March 27 (Box 21, Folder 99)
    - "Swing of the Pendulum" (President and Congress), 1971 March 27 (Box 21, Folder 99)
    - "Busing", 1971 May 1 (Box 21, Folder 99)
    - "War Power", 1971 June 12 (Box 21, Folder 99)
    - "Parochial School Aid", 1971 July 10 (Box 21, Folder 100)
    - "Dead End at Attica", 1971 September 25 (Box 21, Folder 100)
    - "Sharing Responsibility for War", 1971 September 25 (Box 21, Folder 100)
    - "Vacancies on the Court", 1971 October 2 (Box 21, Folder 100)
    - "Order and Attica", 1971 October 23 (Box 21, Folder 101)
    - "Court Appointments", 1971 November 6 (Box 21, Folder 101)
    - "Bus Stop at the House", 1971 November 20 (Box 21, Folder 101)
    - "The Need for a War-Powers Bill", 1972 January 22 (Box 21, Folder 102)
    - "Busing Amendment", 1972 February 26 (Box 21, Folder 102)
    - "Bus Stops", 1972 March 11 (Box 21, Folder 102)
    - "What's Wrong with Nixon's Busing Bills?", 1972 April 22 (Box 21, Folder 102)
    - "Powell's Day" (Supreme Court), 1972 June 10 (Box 21, Folder 103)
    - "Listen Here, John Mitchell", 1972 July 8 (Box 21, Folder 103)
    - "Will the Democrats Survive Miami?", 1972 July 15 (Box 21, Folder 103)
    - "Untangling the Busing Snarl", 1972 September 23, 30 (Box 21, Folder 103)
    - "More on Quotas", 1972 October 28 (Box 22, Folder 104)
    - "Burger and Rehnquist", 1972 November 4 (Box 22, Folder 104)
    - "Crowded Courts", 1972 December 23 & 30 (Box 22, Folder 105)
    - "Death Penalty", 1973 February 3 (Box 22, Folder 105)
    - "Abortion", 1973 February 10 (Box 22, Folder 105)
    - "The Overworked Court", 1973 February 17 (Box 22, Folder 105)
    - "Reconsiderations: Edmund Burke", 1973 March 17 (Box 22, Folder 106)
    - "The Tapes, Cox, Nixon", 1973 September 29 (Box 22, Folder 107)
    - "The Constitutional Tangle", 1973 October 6 (Box 22, Folder 107)
    - "The Agnew Baltimore Brief", 1973 October 13 (Box 22, Folder 107)
    - "What Now?" (Watergate), 1973 November 3 (Box 22, Folder 108)
    - "Impeachment", 1973 November 10 (Box 22, Folder 108)
    - "How Might Mr. Nixon Defend Himself?", 1974 June 1 (Box 22, Folder 108)
    - "Should Rodino Go to Court?", 1974 June 8 (Box 22, Folder 108)
    - "Nelson Case Bill" (subversive activities; unpublished), 1959 (Box 22, Folder 108)
    - Civil Rights -- Labor Unions (unpublished), 1961 May 19 (Box 22, Folder 108)
    - "Freedom Rides Injunction" (unpublished), 1961 June 3 (Box 22, Folder 109)
    - "Adam Clayton Powell" (unpublished), 1961 July 22 (Box 22, Folder 109)
    - "School Prayers" (unpublished), 1961 July 28 (Box 22, Folder 109)
    - "Macy's and the New York Post" (unpublished), 1963 March 23 (Box 22, Folder 109)
    - Ellsberg -- Byrne -- Watergate (unpublished), 1963 July 1 (Box 22, Folder 109)
    - "Webster's Reply to Hayne" (reply to Robert Bork on civil rights; unpublished), 1963 August 1 (Box 22, Folder 109)
    - "Supreme Court" (unpublished), 1964 post-March 16 (Box 22, Folder 109)
    - Untitled draft (civil rights; unpublished), 1964 June 25 (Box 22, Folder 109)
    - "Birth Control and Trial TV" (unpublished), 1965 June 9 (Box 22, Folder 109)
    - "The Relevance of Nuremberg" (unpublished), 1967 July 8 (Box 22, Folder 110)
    - Untitled draft (school desegregation; unpublished), 1970 March 12 (Box 22, Folder 110)
    - "Busing Reply" (unpublished), 1971 December 18 (Box 22, Folder 110)
    - Agnew -- Newsmen (unpublished), 1973 May (Box 22, Folder 110)
    - The Supreme Court, 1960 Term -- Foreword: The Passive Virtues, 1973 October 8 (Box 22, Folder 110)
  - Legal Articles and Journalism
    - "The Original Understanding and the Segregation Decision," Harvard Law Review: memorandum for Felix Frankfurter, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 111)
    - "The Original Understanding and the Segregation Decision," Harvard Law Review: first draft, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 112)
    - "The Original Understanding and the Segregation Decision," Harvard Law Review: second draft, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 113)
    - "The Original Understanding and the Segregation Decision," Harvard Law Review: third draft, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 114)
    - Reply to James F. Byrnes, "The Supreme Court Must Be Curbed," U. S. News & World Report, 1956 June 15 (Box 22, Folder 115)
    - A. Bickel and Harry Wellington, "Legislative Purpose and the Judicial Process: The Lincoln Mills Case," Harvard Law Review, 1957 November (Box 22, Folder 116)
    - "The Court: An Indictment Analyzed," New York Times Magazine, 1958 April 27 (Box 22, Folder 117)
    - "Introduction," Louis Dembitz Brandeis, 1856-1941: A Bibliography, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 117)
    - Reply to Arthur Settel, "The Night Seven Nazis Were Hanged," Commentary, 1960 July (Box 22, Folder 117)
    - Letter to the editor in reply to Pat Watters, "Southern Integrationists Feel Betrayed -- by the North," Harvard Law Review, 1961 November (Box 22, Folder 118)
    - A. Bickel et al., "The Problem of Reapportionment: A Symposium on Baker v. Carr," Yale Law Journal, 1962 November (Box 22, Folder 118)
    - "Reapportionment and Liberal Myths," Commentary, 1963 January (Box 22, Folder 119)
    - A. Bickel et al., letter to the editor (appearance of George Wallace at Yale) Yale Daily News, 1963 September 24 (Box 22, Folder 119)
    - "The Decade of School Desegregation: Progress and Prospects," Columbia Law Review, 1964 February (Box 23, Folder 120)
    - A. Bickel et al., "Arthur Garfield Hays Conference: The Proper Role of the United States Supreme Court in Civil Liberties Cases," Wayne Law Review, 1964 spring (Box 23, Folder 121)
    - "Much More than Law Is Needed," New York Times Magazine, 1964 August 9 (Box 23, Folder 122)
    - "The Civil Rights Act of 1964," Commentary, 1964 August (Box 23, Folder 123)
    - "Applied Politics and the Science of Law: Writings of the Harvard Period," in Wallace Mendelson, ed. Felix Frankfurter: A Tribute, 1964 (Box 23, Folder 124)
    - "John Marshall," Collier's Encyclopedia, 1964 (Box 23, Folder 125)
    - A. Bickel et al., "In Memoriam: Felix Frankfurter," Haryard Law Review, 1965 June (Box 23, Folder 125)
    - "The Role of the Supreme Court of the United States," Texas Law Review, 1966 April (Box 23, Folder 126)
    - A, Bickel et al., "Symposium: Southern Justice: Justice and Compassion," Mississippi Law Journal, 1966 May (Box 23, Folder 126)
    - "Is the Warren Court Too 'Political'?" New York Times Magazine, 1966 September 25 (Box 23, Folder 127)
    - "The Failure, of the Warren Report," Commentary: correspondence, 1966 April-October (Box 23, Folder 128)
    - "The Failure of the Warren Report," Commentary: drafts, 1966 pre-October (Box 23, Folder 129)
    - "The Failure of the Warren Report," Commentary: correspondence, 1966 November-1967 March (Box 23, Folder 130-131)
    - "The Failure of the Warren Report," Commentary: notes on the Report, 1966 pre-October (Box 23, Folder 132)
    - "The Failure of the Warren Report," Commentary: research materials, 1966 pre-October (Box 23, Folder 133)
    - "Leo Sauvage and the Warren Commission," New Leader, 1966 November 21 (Box 23, Folder 134)
    - "The Voting Rights Cases," Supreme Court Review, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 135)
    - "Topics: Reforming the National Conventions," New York Times, 1968 October 19 (Box 23, Folder 136)
    - "Is Electoral Reform the Answer?" Commentary, 1968 December (Box 23, Folder 137)
    - Letter to the editor, "How Democrats Divide," Washington Post, 1969 October 20 (Box 23, Folder 138)
    - "The Case for the Electoral College," American Zionist, 1969 December (Box 23, Folder 138)
    - "The Carswell Nomination: Strict Constructionist or Racist?" Yale Daily News, 1970 February 2 (Box 23, Folder 139)
    - Letter to the editor, "Carswell's Deeds," New York Times, 1970 March 12 (Box 23, Folder 139)
    - Letter to the editor, "The Carswell Evidence," Washington Post, 1970 March 14 (Box 23, Folder 139)
    - "The Making of Supreme Court Justices," New Leader, 1970 May 25 (Box 23, Folder 139)
    - Letter to the editor in reply to Pat Watters, "Southern Integrationists Feel Betrayed — by the North," New York Times Magazine, 1970 June 7 (Box 23, Folder 140)
    - Letter to the editor in reply to editorial on "The President as Educator," Fortune, 1970 July (Box 23, Folder 140)
    - "The Courts: The Need of Change," New York Times, 1970 October 22 (Box 23, Folder 141)
    - "What is John Gardner Up To?" New York Times, 1970 December 21 (Box 23, Folder 141)
    - "Judging the Chicago Trial," Commentary, 1971 January (Box 23, Folder 142)
    - Concurrence with Walter Berns, "Pornography vs. Democracy: The Case for Censorship," Public Interest, 1971 winter (Box 23, Folder 143)
    - "Congress, the President and the Power to Wage War," Chicago-Kent Law Review, 1971 fall-winter (Box 24, Folder 144)
    - "The Supreme Court and Reapportionment," in Nelson W. Polsby, ed. Reapportionment in the 1970s, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 144)
    - A. Bickel and Eugene V. Rostow, "The Power to Make War: A Debate," Yale Law Report, 1971-1972 fall-winter (Box 24, Folder 145)
    - "The Constitution and the War," Commentary, 1972 July (Box 24, Folder 145)
    - Letter to the editor, "View on the War," New York Times, 1972 August 28 (Box 24, Folder 145)
    - "The 'Uninhibited, Robust and Wide Open' First Amendment: From Sullivan to the Pentagon Papers," Commentary, 1972 November (Box 24, Folder 146)
    - "Civil Disobedience and the Duty to Disobey," Gonzaga Law Review, 1973 Spring (Box 24, Folder 146)
    - "Press and Government: Adversaries without Absolutes," Freedom at Issue, 1973 May-June (Box 24, Folder 146)
    - "Should the President Testify? No: Preserve the Executive's Independence," Los Angeles Times, 1973 July 15 (Box 24, Folder 147)
    - "Wretched Tapes (cont.)," New York Times, 1973 August 15 (Box 24, Folder 147)
    - A. Bickel and Arthur Goodhart, "The Arguments for and against Presidential Secrecy," Times (London), 1973 September 3 (Box 24, Folder 148)
    - A. Bickel, et al., "The Constitution: A Colloquy on the Unresolved Issues," Time, 1973 October 8 (Box 24, Folder 148)
    - "Press and Government: Aspects of the Constitutional Position," Freedom at Issue, 1973 September-October (Box 24, Folder 148)
    - "Willis Van Devanter," Dictionary of American Biography, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 149)
    - Foreword to Jacob Javits, Who Makes War?, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 149)
    - "Watergate and the Legal Order," Commentary, 1974 January (Box 24, Folder 150)
    - "Pornography, Censorship and Common Sense: An Interview," Reader's Digest, 1974 February (Box 24, Folder 151)
    - "On Mr. Jaworski's Quarrel with Mr. Nixon," New York Times, 1974 May 23 (Box 24, Folder 151)
    - "Rodino Should Take Nixon to Court," Washington Star-News, 1974 June 9 (Box 24, Folder 152)
    - "Notes on the Constitution," Commentary, 1975 August (Box 24, Folder 152)
    - "The American Situation in Europe," New York Times Magazine, (unpublished), 1954 September 21 (Box 24, Folder 152)
    - Letter to the editor rebutting Fred Rodell, New York Times Magazine, (unpublished), 1960 June 12 (Box 24, Folder 153)
    - "Justice and Protection in the South," New York Times Magazine, (unpublished), 1965 November (Box 24, Folder 153)
    - "Should the Warren Report Be Re-Examined?" New York Times Magazine, (unpublished), 1966 November-December (Box 24, Folder 153)
    - "Supreme Court Essay," Life, (unpublished), 1971 (Box 24, Folder 153)
    - "School Integration," Los Angeles Times, (unpublished), 1972 January-July (Box 24, Folder 153)
  - Book Reviews
    - Mr. Justice, by A. Dunham and P. Kurland, eds., Harvard Law Review, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 154)
    - The Legacy of Holmes and Brandeis, by S. Konefsky, and The Brandeis Reader, by E. Pollack, New England Quarterly, 1957 June (Box 24, Folder 154)
    - Mr. Baruch, by M. Coit, Yale Law Journal, 1958 January (Box 24, Folder 155)
    - The Bill of Rights, by L. Hand, New Republic, 1958 May 12 (Box 24, Folder 155)
    - Marble Palace — The Supreme Court in American Life, by J. Frank, New Republic, 1958 November 3 (Box 24, Folder 156)
    - Douglas of the Supreme Court, by V. Countryman, ed., and The Public Papers of Chief Justice Earl Warren, by H. Christman, New Republic, 1959 September 14 (Box 24, Folder 156)
    - The Supreme Court from Taft to Warren, by A. Mason, Journal of Legal Education, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 157)
    - Legacy of Supression, by L. Levy, New Republic, 1960 July 18 (Box 24, Folder 157)
    - The American Supreme Court, by R. McCloskey, and Felix Frankfurter: Scholar on the Bench, by Ho Thomas, New Republic, 1960 December 19 (Box 24, Folder 157)
    - The Legal Conscience: Selected Papers of Felix S. Cohen, by L. Cohen, ed., New Republic, 1961 April 24 (Box 24, Folder 158)
    - Principles, Politics and Fundamental Law, by H. Wechsler, New York Post, 1961 May 7 (Box 24, Folder 158)
    - The Faces of Justice, by S. Bedford, New Republic, 1961 June 26 (Box 24, Folder 158)
    - Felix Frankfurter: Scholar on the Bench, by H. Thomas, Mississippi Valley Historical Review, 1961 June (Box 24, Folder 159)
    - Justice Holmes, Natural Law, and the Supreme Court, by F. Biddle, New Republic, 1961 November 6 (Box 24, Folder 159)
    - The Predicament of Democratic Man, by E. Cahn, New Republic, 1962 February 5 (Box 24, Folder 159)
    - Portrait of a Philosopher: Morris R. Cohen in Life and Letters, by L. Rosenfield, Law Library Journal, 1963 May (Box 24, Folder 160)
    - A Commentary on the Constitution of the United States, by B. Schwartz, New York Times, [1963?] (Box 24, Folder 160)
    - A Commentary on the Constitution …, by B. Schwartz, Columbia Law Review, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 160)
    - Justice on Trial, by A. L. Todd, New Republic, 1964 August 8 (Box 24, Folder 161)
    - Federalism and Civil Rights, by B. Marshall, New Republic, 1964 October 31 (Box 24, Folder 161)
    - Invitation to an Inquest, by W. and M. Schneir, Commentary, 1966 January (Box 24, Folder 162)
    - Law and Politics in the Supreme Court, by M. Shapiro, and Elements of Judicial Strategy, by W. Murphy, Political Science Quarterly, 1966 March (Box 24, Folder 163)
    - Protest: Sacco-Vanzetti and the Intellectuals, by D. Felix, New Republic, 1966 April 2 (Box 24, Folder 163)
    - The Death of a President, by W. Manchester, New Haven Register, 1967 April 9 (Box 24, Folder 164)
    - The Law at Harvard, by A. Sutherland, New York Times Book Review, 1967 June 25 (Box 24, Folder 164)
    - The Lawyers, by M. Mayer, New Republic, 1967 September 23 (Box 24, Folder 164)
    - Warren: The Man, The Court, the Era, by J. Weaver, New Republic, 1967 October 7 (Box 24, Folder 165)
    - Six Seconds in Dallas, by J. Thompson, and Accessories After the Fact, by S. Meagher, New Republic, 1967 December 23 (Box 24, Folder 165)
    - Search and Seizure and the Supreme Court, by J. Landynski, Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1968 January (Box 24, Folder 166)
    - Roosevelt and Frankfurter, by M. Freedman, New Republic, 1968 February 3 (Box 24, Folder 166)
    - After the Assassination, by J. Sparrow, New Republic, 1968 March 23 (Box 24, Folder 167)
    - A Citizen's Dissent, by M. Lane, New Republic, 1968 June 22 (Box 24, Folder 167)
    - The End of Obscenity, by C. Rembar, Commentary, 1968 November (Box 24, Folder 168)
    - The Garrison Case, by M. Brener, New York Times Book Review, 1969 November 30 (Box 24, Folder 168)
    - Justice, by R. Harris, New Republic, 1970 April 18 (Box 24, Folder 168)
    - Congress v. The Supreme Court, by R. Berger, American Historical Review, 1970 June (Box 24, Folder 169)
    - Justice Joseph Story, by G. Dunne, New York Times Book Review, 1971 May 30 (Box 24, Folder 169)
    - Foreign Affairs and the Constitution, by L. Henkin, National Review, 1973 August 17 (Box 24, Folder 169)
    - Three Faces of Power, by A. Berle, Book World (not published), 1968 January (Box 24, Folder 169)
- PUBLIC SPEAKING, 1956-1974; Series IV; 1 linear feet (5 boxes)
  Series IV, PUBLIC SPEAKING, is similar in content to Series III. For every title listed there is some form of the text, most often a typed draft or handwritten notes, and usually there is also correspondence with the sponsor of the presentation. Most of the texts are speeches before academic or professional audiences, but there are also notes for after-dinner remarks and transcripts of panel discussions and broadcasts.
  The titles and the papers related to each title are in chronological order, with unidentified notes and texts at the end of the series.
  - "The Militant Faith of Mr. Justice Brandeis": address, Yale University Hillel Foundation, 1956 November 9